Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
♪ from the dusty May sun ♪
♪ her looming shadow grows ♪
♪ hidden in the branches ♪
♪ of the poison creosote ♪
♪ she twines her spines up slowly ♪
♪ towards the boiling sun ♪
♪ and when I touched her skin ♪
♪ my fingers ran with blood ♪
♪ when the last light warms the rocks ♪
♪ and the rattlesnakes unfold ♪
♪ the mountain cats will come ♪
♪ to drag away your bones ♪
♪ and rise with me forever ♪
♪ across the silent sand ♪
♪ and the stars will be your eyes ♪
♪ and the wind will be my hands ♪
True Detective - 1x06
"Haunted Houses"
I'm gonna go make my rounds.
Only got in.
I'll check back with you
in about 20 minutes.
I-- I didn't know Audrey's
dad's a cop. I, uh...
I didn't mean no disrespect.
Yes, sir, we didn't mean
any disrespect.
Audrey's 16.
We got you on statch rape.
You know that, right?
You know what happens
to pretty boys like you
who go up to the farm
on statch charges?
Look at that.
Door come open.
Y'all want to step out a bit,
take some air?
No, sir.
I think that you're
a little angry right now.
You telling me how I feel?
That's patronizing.
Two choices...
we do this here
with an understanding
that not you or any
of your river rat boys
comes within a hundred
yards of my daughter,
or... file those charges.
Got a lot of brothers in Angola
who love to owe me a favor.
Now come on out here.
Come on.
Come out here.
Man's game charges
a man's price.
Take that away from this
if nothing else.
Ohh!
Aah!
Please!
Look, I'm sorry.
Disciplinary reports
say he was acting unstable even before.
What happened, you and him?
Two formal reprimands,
suspension.
Your major back then, Salter...
wrote...
"Manic state" right here.
No, he-- he, uh,
started pulling
lost time more, but OK.
And for whatever reason, he...
started working something
that I didn't know about.
Old missing persons.
What you want, man?
Nothing here for you.
I'm with the
State Police Department.
If you're Terry Guidry, I'd like
to talk to you about your boy.
Sheriff call for
a search party?
They had a marine
unit out there.
Spotlight, everything, and...
nothing.
Four weeks later, wildlife
fisheries find his pirogue...
all broke up.
Said it coulda been a gator.
Where'd Sonny go to school?
Queen of Angels.
One of them Tuttle schools.
We didn't sleep them first
4 weeks Sonny was missing.
Drove his mama crazy.
Sh-she...
She thought she heard him
under the water...
calling for her.
Hey, man, look.
Why don't you just get
out of here, please?
I don't want to get arrested.
Just-- just get...
before I do something to you.
If it's wrong, I want it right.
It's all I got.
We're not gonna talk to you,
personal matters
like this, without you--
you don't want to talk about
something, it's OK, no problem.
You sure we can't get
you any coffee, a...
No, thank you.
You worried about your ex?
It's OK. We are not looking
at him, and nobody wants to.
Well, what are you
looking for, from me?
Well, perspective, I guess.
Something went down, 2002.
Your ex-husband's
partner, Rustin Cohle.
In a former life,
I used to exhaust myself
navigating crude men
who thought they were clever,
so ask your questions
or I'm leaving.
That's a cop's wife, all right.
Not anymore.
We're not trying
to work you, ma'am.
Word of honor.
We need to know about
Rustin Cohle in 2002.
Why he took off, what
he'd done since.
Have you had any contact with
Cohle, Mrs. Sawyer, since 2002?
- No, I haven't.
- But you knew him well enough.
I mean, he was your
husband's partner.
Rust?
Yeah, I knew him.
Not as well as other people.
Why, exactly, are you
asking about him?
Something bad happened.
Maybe Cohle's involved.
More we look at him,
it don't look good.
Something went real wrong
with him a long time ago.
I knew Rust to be a good man,
so I can't imagine
what I can offer.
I mean, Rust knew
exactly who he was...
and there was
no talking him out of it.
You know, Marty's
single big problem was
that he never really
knew himself,
so he never really knew
what to want.
But I'm big enough to not stay
angry at someone for that...
not after all this time.
Receipt in the bag?
Great.
Thank you so much.
- Have a good day.
- Thank you.
Can I help you
with anything, sir?
Oh, yeah, uh, please.
I was thinking about this one.
_
Fuck.
Excuse me. Can I get
a dirty Martini, please?
- Coming right up.
- Thanks.
Big weekend planned?
Oh. Yeah.
Uh, heh! Yeah.
Has all the makings
of a good time.
You're a cop, aren't you?
How'd you know?
I, uh,
I think I saw you
before, years back.
You get in some trouble?
No. Uh...
you came around this
place I was staying,
asking about a girl.
Oh.
Marty.
Beth.
We're closed.
You always hit the bottle this
early in the day, Reverend?
Who are you?
You don't remember me?
Hmm?
I came to see you at your
revival tent, January of '95.
Looks like you gave that up.
Mid-eighties. You were still
with the Tuttle ministry then.
What do you know about a Tuttle
organization that was set up
to finance rural schools?
It was called Wellspring.
It was an Evangelical initiative
to provide religious education
as an alternative to public
school in the rural communities.
Yeah, part of the reason there was
so many dropouts in the state,
a lot of kids had
to bus an hour or more.
You know about that school
on Pelican Island?
I don't know it specific,
but there was one...
in 1988.
Accusations of children
being interfered with.
I never found anything on that.
It was-- it was kept
internal, I think.
Maybe it was nothing,
maybe people was paid.
It's got nothing
to do with me, mind you.
I was going to school
in Baton Rouge.
Gossip around the seminary,
but we didn't give
credence to rumors.
Why'd you leave?
Bureaucracy.
Politics.
Don't lie to me.
Why'd you leave?
Part of our lay duties
was custodial.
One night, cleaned the
senior minister's library.
I knocked over
a very old volume,
"The Letters
of Telios DeLorca."
Twelfth-century Franciscan
mystic, very obscure.
When I picked up the book,
this little folder falls out.
Little folder of pictures.
Pictures of children.
Naked.
Looked like they was sleeping.
And what'd you do?
I took it over to the morals
officer, Deacon Farrar.
He was close to Tuttle,
vice president of the college.
He didn't do nothin'?
No, he seemed... he got angry
that I brought it to him.
He even intimated that maybe I
was confessing to something.
I mean, I had to prove
to him that I wasn't.
He promised to look into it...
I'd left by the time
Wellspring shut down.
Why'd you quit
the revival, hmm?
Oh, our last two tents
was vandalized.
I lost heart.
Little too much of this.
All my life, I wanted
to be nearer to God.
But the only nearness...
silence.
Oh, it wasn't
as bad as it seemed.
Better than most.
Jan was a decent lady.
I heard she sold
the ranch a while back.
I can't believe that was you.
Saved up money for a place,
got a straight job.
I'd run off from a bad
situation when we first met.
Well, it's just--
just so great
how you turned
everything around.
Look at you.
Well, you were
a big hero in the papers.
Aw, they made a bigger deal
of that than it was.
I ain't been...
too heroic of late.
Just...
You're a good man.
Anybody can see that.
I saw it the first
time I met you.
God gave us these flaws,
and something I learned--
He doesn't see them as flaws.
There is nothing wrong
with the way He made us.
The universe forgives all.
You want some bourbon?
Mmm.
Oh, yeah.
What happened in 2002?
You-- you pulled
our last case?
Charmaine Boudreaux?
It was in all the papers.
"Marshland Medea."
You know who Medea was?
- Yeah.
- We had a lot of static
after that, me and him.
That was a bad one.
I always thought
it contributed,
Rust's state of mind
when he walked.
SIDs.
What is that?
It's a 4-letter word,
S-I-D-S,
but, I mean...
what is it?
It's an old word,
like a curse.
Not a language anyone speaks.
But it's what happened
to Jessica,
your first.
They said... your second,
Jody, was 23 days old.
The autopsy showed no
signs of trauma, so...
SIDs.
I lost one myself, Charmaine.
I lost a marriage, too.
Now your third,
and you had him last year.
Jesus, lady, you ever hear
of a fuckin' condom?
Birth control's a sin.
A child is a wonderful thing.
A child is wonderful.
You see, sometimes people...
mistake a child as an answer
for something,
you know, like a way
to change their story.
Charmaine, have you ever
heard of something called...
Munchausen by Proxy?
No.
At exactly 4:49 AM,
the sleep apnea monitor that
was hooked up to your child
was unplugged...
for 36 minutes.
Then it was plugged back
in, and by that time,
the child's vitals
had flat-lined.
Charmaine, I need you
to talk to me
about some things.
OK?
OK.
How's it going?
He's getting it.
You should sign that.
The newspapers
are gonna be tough on you...
and prison is
very... very hard
on people who hurt kids.
If you get the opportunity,
you should kill yourself.
What?
What? Please.
Oh, just-- wait.
Jesus.
This evil bitch.
I called Pennsylvania,
tried to get homicides
on the first two
kids, but looks like
we may only have the one.
- Well, it's still life.
- Yeah.
Good job.
Listen, Marty,
type that up for me, will ya?
Excuse me?
You got somewhere to be?
This confession is,
like, 40 pages.
What, and you got somewhere to be?
Come on, man.
You want me to tie your
shoes for you, too?
Hey.
I think we
actually need your signature
on the third page,
if you have it.
The fuck's with
the attitude, huh?
Like my time's less than yours?
Oh, you got things
to do, Marty?
Need to go home to the
family, play with the kids?
Don't get up my ass
- just 'cause you ain't gettin' any.
- Oh.
You should have held on
to your woman.
Gettin' laid was good for you.
Goddamn.
You moron.
You, these people, this place.
It's like you eat
your fuckin' young
and that's all just fine
as long as you got
something to salute, huh?
What's going on with you, man?
I mean, Salter asked about it.
Iberia called.
You been going around
bothering people,
trying to open up old cases.
I am working.
I have things to do.
So type the report, man.
That's how we do.
I get people to talk,
you write the stats.
It's worked out well
for you so far.
I'm the only one
ever took up for you.
Ever.
You know what it's like
being your partner, huh?
Fuck you.
No, buddy, without me...
there is no you.
So type the fuckin'
report, man.
We've had behaviorists
in with her.
It's regressive catatonia.
Seven years now.
If she shows any distress,
responds in any way negatively,
- we're gonna have to ask you to leave.
- Of course.
- OK.
- I was actually one of the men
who found Kelly at that
place 7 years back.
She's right here.
Kelly.
Now, you may not remember, but
you and I met a long time ago.
I want to ask you a
question about those men
that hurt you way back then.
Do you remember if there
were more than two?
Was there anyone else?
The man with the scars
was the worst.
My Lord.
What scars?
The giant.
He made me watch
what he did to Billy.
The scars on the giant,
were they-- were they on his face?
His face.
All right, Rose,
I need-- I need Haldol.
Stat, please...
What are you doing, Cohle?
Riling up people,
opening old cases.
Iberia Sheriff's talking
jurisdictional complaint.
Something's going on, Major,
along the coast.
Women...
children disappearing.
Nobody hears about it,
nobody puts them together.
First I'm hearing
about it, Boss.
Puts what together, Cohle?
Someone, maybe more than one,
is killing people, Major,
and they've been doing it
for a long time.
Yeah, you got any bodies?
You got something actually
applies to your job
as a homicide detective?
Know what he did?
Goes and visits Kelly Reider,
sent her into a screaming fit.
Look, either we don't find
them or they don't get connected.
I don't know which,
and I can't decide
if it's a cover-up
or the garden-variety
incompetence here.
I mean, it has to do
with those boys we got
in '95, the Dora Lange killing.
We didn't get them all.
You're building
something in your head.
Women, then children.
Now they're getting no press,
the way things in the
bayou get no press.
And it's happening
in the same area
where that Voudon shit
goes down,
and it's happening in the same area
where those schools were set up.
What the fuck schools
you talking about?
Tuition reimbursement programs
for rural and Christian schools
founded by Billy Lee Tuttle.
Yeah.
Think about it.
Back in '95, why was he so fired
up to get his ass down here?
He comes barging in
with his task force.
Fuck, before we even got started
on the case, he took it over.
Why?
'Cause he recognized
something in it.
We're in a muddy
swamp here, man.
The alligators are
swimming around us,
and we don't even know whether
they're there. You know why?
'Cause we don't see 'em.
I caught
zero logic in all that.
And that last bit?
Pure gibberish.
How about we track
all the missing persons
within 10 miles
of every Walmart, huh?
Right along the I-10. Why don't
we go after Sam Walmart?
I'm fixing to pull you
for mental exhaustion, man.
You want to stay on?
Do not ever, ever say that
to anyone in State again.
Sure.
That's some fuckin' nerve
you got, buddy.
You need to take a few steps
back, Rust, right now.
All right. Hey.
No more visiting
victims' families.
You will stop trying
to turn missing persons
into homicides, as you
do not have any bodies.
That's a direct fuckin'
order, you hear me?
You do anything else, I'll have you on
insubordination, and I will suspend you.
Please, take some time.
Go on one of them
fishing tours or something.
All right?
Get yourself together.
And a little
less than two years ago,
Tuttle overdosed.
Accidentally, supposed.
You mentioned that already.
Couple weeks before he died,
Tuttle's house in
Shreveport was broken into.
Found out his Baton
Rouge one was, too.
Wasn't reported.
So?
So your man gets a
hard-on for Tuttle.
Man's house gets broken
into right after Cohle
turns back up in the state.
What's he been
doing since, here?
Drinking, bartending?
Dude with a mind
like that, you think
that's all he get up to?
Marty, he'd
never went anywhere.
He never left.
He's been right here doing
bad things a long time.
Hey, hey, hey.
Hold up now.
Been in this room
a long time, gentlemen.
Whatever Rust is
or was or became...
don't call me again.
I won't help you.
We're trying
to help him, Marty.
Hey, did you have a good day?
Mm-hmm.
Well, why don't you get
that bathroom cleaned
finally, huh, get all
the toothpaste up?
Thanks.
Marty, I didn't know
you were home.
Oh, yeah, I'm just cleaning up.
Be out in a sec.
I'll heat up something.
Hey, those flowers
came in nice.
You were right. They really
brighten up the yard.
Hey,
I was thinking we're
due for a date night,
don't you think, you and me?
I want to dress up and go
for a nice dinner,
the movies.
Yeah? Does that
sound good?
Honey?
Sure.
Ah.
Oh. Thanks, hon.
Nice.
So, is my eldest still
offended by my presence?
Huh?
Yeah, I don't mind.
I'm happy just to sit here with
3 beautiful women watching...
What is this?
"Dumb Blondes
in Cracker Country"?
Hey, hon?
Do me a favor, find the game?
Here you go.
I have to study.
Good girl.
Rolls right onto
victory lane into Daytona USA.
Davis with the steal.
Pops it in to Hudson.
Hudson trying to move the ball down
the court, and a foul on Flowers.
What?
Nothing.
Now, this pasta is great.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
I love you.
Thank you.
You turn it down some, please?
Sure, hon.
Ahem.
How's that?
We were talking once
about growing up parents.
I said something about
forgiveness, and he said
that there was no such thing
as forgiveness...
that people just have
short memories.
You think Cohle
was wrong about that?
Forgiveness?
Less and less.
Hi.
Get you a drink, Miss?
Thank you.
Uh, sure.
A vodka Martini, extra dirty.
Margaret.
Bruce. Hi.
Hi.
So you, uh, waiting
for someone?
No.
You and, uh,
Marty split prior, right?
In '95?
Are either of you married?
- Got an ex.
- Mmm.
Still on the first.
It's difficult to admit defeat.
Marty quit drinking,
found religion for a while.
I didn't love that.
To be honest,
I preferred him before;
he had a sense of humor then.
But we stayed together 7 more
years, some of it pretty good.
2002?
Cohle's bad year, too.
Rust was an intense man,
but he had integrity.
He was responsible.
Not a lot of responsible
people in the world.
Reverend, thanks for taking
the time to see me
on such short notice.
Of course, Detective, please.
It's a very
interesting... building.
This was the first.
Built it in 1980.
The rest of the campus
grew around it.
Now, I remembered
you, of course.
People of this state
owe you a great deal.
Not as much as they owe you.
Charitable organizations,
education initiatives.
Thank you. We're very
proud of our ministries.
I don't do as much
preaching as I used to,
but the legacy program
is more my focus now,
the things like the
State Policemen's Charity-- but...
what did you want
to talk about, son?
The Wellspring program,
mid-eighties through
the early nineties.
You remember that?
Well, of course
I remember, yeah.
I'm trying to locate
old personnel,
faculty, but I'm having a little
bit of trouble acquiring names.
Well, the program was shut down
officially, you know, maybe 10 years ago.
I never had much ground
contact with it,
but it involved a number
of private schools--
enterprises,
you understand--
that would adopt our standard
of curriculum and, in return,
receive tuition reimbursement
for underprivileged students.
You got any files,
any list of faculty?
Well, that's what I'm getting at, is
that these were private institutions,
so you'd have to track down their
administrators, I believe.
That's the thing.
See, all the schools
dissolved with the program,
and I'm trying
to find some tax info,
but there were
religious exemptions.
Well, there's our
archives, of course.
Now, we did lose
a lot of files,
had some flooding of one
of the sub-floors.
But, you know, I think I should
put you together with one
of our clerical workers and see if
they can't help you find something.
Thank you. Listen,
before you do that...
former deacon of yours,
Austin Farrar.
That was very,
very unfortunate.
Yet he was dismissed.
Evidence had accrued.
It became apparent
that Austin had
implemented
certain... funds.
Well, "Embezzling" is the word.
We elected to handle it
internally,
rather than pursuing
formal charges.
And then he had
his... accident.
I'd heard he had taken it hard,
drinking.
I've seen more souls lost
down a bottle than any pit.
At the same time,
it's hard to trust a man
who can't trust himself
with a beer, don't you think?
Hmm.
But what's this
all about now? Um...
Wellspring program,
Austin Farrar?
Dead women and children.
Terrible.
That's terrible.
How is that what
you're working on?
Oh, I can't say anything about
it at this point, Reverend.
I'd like to set you up
with a clerk.
You can look at, uh,
whatever information
we still have
from Wellspring.
Why'd the Wellspring program
shut down, Reverend?
It couldn't sustain its costs.
The whole idea was to
provide an alternative
to the kind of secular,
globalized education
that our public schools
were promoting.
When we get the school
voucher program instituted,
we'll reintroduce the idea.
People should have a choice in
education, like anything else.
Hmm.
Steve, would you show
the detective
to our old archives
for outside ministries?
- Yes, sir.
- I'll call ahead.
I'm gonna come back for that.
Reverend, thank you
for your time today.
Godspeed, Detective.
You'll be in my thoughts.
Oh, just the one more time.
I just need it-- I just
need it one more time.
Beth, if you knew
the day I just had--
Oh, then tell me about it.
I want to hear about it.
Oh...
no, you do not.
I really wanted to see you.
I've been thinking
about something all week.
Don't.
Ever since last time.
Don't, OK?
I just--
Haven't been able to think of
anything else, tell you the truth.
Ohh...
like what?
I've been thinking.
I think...
I want you to fuck me
in my ass.
Uh, Beth.
I've never done that
before, but
I think I want you
to do it to me.
I want you to feel better.
You out
of your goddamn mind, hmm?
What'd I tell you?
You're fuckin'
unbelievable, boy.
You know about this?
Uh, I'm not sure what
we're talking about here.
Your partner here,
he braced Billy Lee Tuttle.
Oh, "Braced"?
Are you fucking kidding me?
It was a friendly conversation.
Hey, dipshit,
you don't get to decide what
kind of conversation it was.
Why'd you talk
to Billy Lee Tut--
And you, look at--
you look like you haven't seen
your own bed
in a couple days, huh?
Yeah? The fuck is wrong
with you two?
Ahem.
Well, I-- I can't speak for Rust,
but I got the flu.
I didn't know
that was going around.
Look, this is exactly
what I'm talking about.
If he was pissed off after
the conversation we had,
then I am on
to fucking something.
Shut the fuck up.
I told you.
I fuckin' told you!
And human tampon here heard me.
Badge and gun, Cohle.
You're suspended.
One month without pay.
Repeated rank insubordination,
misallocation
departmental resources.
- Come on.
- Leroy.
Come on, that's over the top.
Don't you fuckin' Leroy me!
I told you both!
Cut the shit!
It's done.
Badge and gun, Cohle.
Oh, and, uh, before
your official reinstatement,
you have 30 hours mandated
departmental counseling.
You fuckin' serious?
This guy, right?
I got to kick you
in the fuckin' head.
I'm the person least
in need of counseling
in this entire fuckin' state.
You ain't acting
right, you don't sound right.
You're up my ass,
and you were warned.
What?
He's doing it again.
He's been doing it.
I can't live with it.
I can't deal with it,
not again.
Did you know?
No.
What are you doing in here?
What happened?
I'm off the job.
That's not what I mean.
You can't live like this.
You know, people
that give me advice,
I reckon they're talking
to themselves.
What are you doing?
Some people, no matter where
they look, they see themselves.
Be honest...
with me now.
What the fuck are you
doing here?
Huh?
I'm sorry.
You know...
it wasn't you.
Really. I...
I wasn't even sure
I could do it,
- 'cause seventeen years is a long time.
- Huh?
You know...
I almost went with a...
with a stranger, a bar.
I'm sorry, Rust.
He'll have
to go, you see, because this
he won't live with.
Get the fuck out of here.
This...
You get the fuck--
This will hurt him.
Get the fuck out
of here right now.
I'm sorry, but thank you.
You get the fuck out of here.
- I'm--
- Get the fuck out of here!
Do you know what was going
on with Cohle around that time?
No.
I knew that he got suspended
and that he quit
after he and Marty had his...
they had their thing.
That's it.
So your split with Marty...
that had nothing
to do with Cohle?
No.
Hey, hon.
Hi, Marty.
How you doing?
Sit down.
OK.
I have to tell you something.
I saw the pictures
on your phone.
"B"?
- Now, honey--
- Nice ass, Marty.
- No, I--
- I was maybe always a little
- too skinny for you.
- No.
I cannot help it if some
crazy bitch sent--
I slept with someone.
And you know him.
You're close.
Who?
It was Rust.
I fucked your partner Rust.
Oh.
Now, what-- what
are you saying?
What-- what are you--
what the fuck are you saying to me?
I already told you.
You fucking whore.
You don't know the half of it.
To tell you the truth,
I haven't been fucked
like that since
before the girls.
Do it.
Do it!
At least I'll have something
to explain to your daughters.
Get your fucking hands off me.
Coward.
Cohle's outside.
Does he know he's suspended?
I was coming for
my files, Marty.
Hey, hey, hey!
Whoa!
Come on, guys, stop this shit.
Come on, Marty.
Come on, swing, Marty!
You're gettin' your ass kicked!
Oh, my God.
Get Salter.
Get Salter!
Hurry up! Stop them!
Hey!
Stop!
Oh!
Stay down, Marty.
Come on now.
Don't do it!
Hop up!
Get up, get up!
Work it out.
- Calm down, Marty.
- All right, that's enough now.
Hey!
All right, back off!
- Come on! Come on! Get him out of here!
- Come on, Hart!
Get him the fuck out of here!
Fuck you!
- Calm down, Marty!
- Cohle!
You better calm
your shit right now!
Get inside!
You standing around
watching this shit?!
Get the fuck inside!
I'm gonna
kill you, motherfucker!
Get him inside.
We ain't done here!
- Get him inside.
- We ain't done here!
Stop this shit.
I'm gonna need some
fuckin' detail here, you two.
It's a personal
matter between us, Boss.
Is there anybody
pressin' charges?
Not me.
You want
to say anything, Cohle?
No.
This man right here
is the only pal you had,
you understand that?
Fuck him.
I ain't his pal.
I quit.
You serious?
I'll send you a letter.
Yeah, fuck this.
Fuck this world, man.
Nice hook, Marty.
You're not gonna go
into this, huh? Really?
You two fucked each
other up pretty good.
No shit.
What about when
he quit? Any idea why?
Maybe it was
old stuff between them...
the way they
always rubbed wrong.
I never learned
what it was about.
Marty.
Rust.
Long time.
Change your hair?
Thought maybe we should talk.
Yeah?
Buy you a beer?
Sure. I'll follow you.
Actually, why don't you
buy me a beer?
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com